Nature and Character of a Defect Opportunity
Welcome to this segment on Six Sigma.
We’re going to look at a very interesting concept.
It's been a lot of controversy for a long time
and that's the idea of defect opportunities.
So, what is a defect opportunity? Well it’s really pretty simple.
I think a lot of people over the years have made a big deal out of it.
We even went through in the early 90's through Texas Instruments,
at their defense group, called the opportunity wars.
It got that bitter, over what constitutes a defect opportunity.
Well, after many years of frustrating debate. That was good debate. Healthy debate.
We finally come to realize that a defect opportunity is nothing more
than anything you measure
and report
on a regular basis. That's a defect opportunity. So, let me say this.
If I had a little product here, a little widget gizmo, could be a radio
or I could have a process, consider that the product.
Like a masseuse has a service process. A massage, you experience the process.
This is a piece of hardware. I could look at a legal defense from a legal point of view.
Anything. Whatever that may be.  It’s full of opportunities.
So, let's take something that's important to us that we value.
If we measure it and report it, then that's a defect opportunity. That simple.
Now, what we’re going to do is look at this in a little greater detail.
But fundamentally a defect opportunity, an opportunity,
is a set of conditions that is favorable to an end.
Think of that. It's a set of conditions,
that is favorable
to some end.
Now in this case, the end we’re talking about is a defect.
A defect. So, a set of conditions favorable to some end.
Or a defect. Well, let's take a look at it.
We’re going to break this down and understand this concept of a defect opportunity.
Condition is a standard. If I have an upper spec limit and a lower spec limit,
I have a standard. That's a condition. Think about it.
If I had activity and I had no standard to gauge my activity against.
There can never be a defect, if that's gone.
Then I also need now, a process capability.
If there is no process capability,
then all there is, is a potential opportunity, see.
That design specification is a potential opportunity.
If there is a distribution of capability but no design specification,
there's potential opportunity. But when that design.
When that process capability is interfaced
with the design opportunity, then we have a defect opportunity.
Now, let’s think about that for second. I’m going to blow this up again, even larger.
For our discussion here. Here again is that upper spec.
Here is that lower spec. And,
here is the process distribution.
Remember, it takes both to be present.
Upper. I’ll just draw that across there real nice, so we can see that.
Now, this region right here in the red.
This is the probability of a defect.
That's the probability of a defect. Everything in the green here,
is the probability of yield, or what's good.
This is what's good, that's in the green. Now,
if I don't have a process capability. There's no probability of defects.
If I don't have a standard, then there's nothing to declare these as red.
There’s no reference point, high watermark, to declare them as red.
So, everything would be green. Only when I interface my process
with my design, do I have probability of defect.
If there is no interface, guess what?
There is no probability.
So, you can't have a defect. If there's no probability for a defect.
Therefore, to have a defect opportunity,
then the probability of a defect must be greater than zero.
Now, think about that. If there's no distribution, no capability, there's no probability.
Probability of defect is zero. If there's a distribution but no standards,
probability is zero.
Only, when I marry the process
to the design. Does the idea of probability
come into being. Once it comes into being. If the probability is greater than zero,
then there is an opportunity for
defect, that simple. Thus, we have the idea
of probability of defect or defect opportunity.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.